Guide to the Paul H. Silverstone, Class of 1953, Yale College, Postcard Collection Documenting Yale University
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Paul H. Silverstone, Class of 1953, Yale College, postcard collection documenting Yale University
1900-1950
RU 946
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.75
(3 boxes)
The collection consists of souvenir postcards of Yale, most of which depict buildings and grounds. Also included are postcards depicting Yale athletics, symbols, and student life.
Silverstone, Paul H.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were a gift of Paul H. Silverstone, 2004, 2008.
Arrangement
The rmaterials are arranged by accession, thereunder alphabetically by publisher.
Scope and Contents
The materials consists of souvenir postcards of Yale, most of which depict buildings and grounds. Also included are postcards depicting Yale athletics, symbols, and student life.
Postcards; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Postcards, circa 1900-1950; Accession 2004-A-115
  - Albertype (Box 1)
  - American News (Box 1)
  - American Art (Box 1)
  - American Art Works - Star Art Co. (Box 1)
  - American Scene (Box 1)
  - Blue Ribbon (Box 1)
  - Bosselman (Box 1)
  - Collotype (Box 1)
  - Danziger & Berman (Box 1)
  - Detroit (Box 1)
  - EPJ (Box 1)
  - Edward P. Judd (Box 1)
  - Howe & Stetson (Box 1)
  - Leighton (Box 1)
  - Livingston (Box 1)
  - Edw. Malley (Box 1)
  - McKee (Box 1)
  - Metropolitan News (Box 1)
  - Paul C. Koeber (Box 1)
  - Rotograph - National Art - Solart (Box 1)
  - Souvenir (Box 1)
  - Stoddard (Box 1)
  - Tuck (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 1)
  - Real photos (Box 1)
  - Yale multiview (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous buildings (Box 2)
  - Linen (Box 2)
  - Turnpike (Box 2)
  - Non-postcard material (Box 2)
  - Binder containing postcards (most not buildings) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Inventory of postcards (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Postcards, circa 1905-1940; Accession 2008-A-182
  - American Art Post Card Co.
    - Bingham Hall, Yale University, circa 1930 (Box 1)
  - A. J. Ayer (H. P. Co.)
    - Rock marking first site of Yale College, founded 1701, Saybrook, Connecticut, circa 1910 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Livingston
    - Elm Street looking north from College Street, New Haven, CT, circa 1910 (Box 1)
  - The Color Studio
    - Stiles & Morse Colleges (Box 1)
    - Yale University campus in winter (Box 1)
  - Danziger & Berman
    - Berkeley Oval, Yale (#107), 1914 (Box 1)
    - Old Yale Library (#114), circa 1940 (Box 1)
    - Scroll & Key Senior Society Building, Yale University (Box 1)
  - Detroit Publishing Co.
    - Dining Hall, Yale University (#8674) (Box 1)
  - E.P.J. Co.
    - Yale Field football game, Yale Field (#1420), 1911 (Box 1)
  - Edward Malley Co.
    - Phelps Hall, Yale University, circa 1900 (Box 1)
  - Edward P. Judd Co.
    - Vanderbilt-Sheff Campus & Dormitories, Yale, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Frankenberger Co.
    - Peabody Museum, Yale (Box 1)
  - Harold Hahn Co.
    - Harkness Tower, Memorial Quadrangle, Yale (#14), 1935 (Box 1)
    - Sterling Law School Building, Yale University (#14), 1938 (Box 1)
    - Court, Sterling Law School, Yale University (#28), 1935 (Box 1)
    - Yale Theatre, Yale University (#55), circa 1935 (Box 1)
    - Blount Avenue, Yale University, New Haven, CT, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Bird's eye view showing Hotel Taft in the center of everything, circa 1920 (Box 1)
  - Illustrated Postal Card Co.
    - Woolsey Hall, Yale (Box 1)
  - Lawrence and Gorham
    - Connecticut/Yale rhyme, circa 1907 (Box 1)
  - Morris Berman
    - View in Campus, Yale College, 1918 (Box 1)
    - The Campus, Yale University, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Parker Publisher
    - President Taft delivering speech on the steps of Woodbridge Hall, Yale College, 1909, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Rotograph Co.
    - Woolsey Hall, Yale, circa 1905 (Box 1)
  - Ullman Manufacturing
    - "College" series #993. sketch of woman with muff superimposed on blue "Yale", 1908 (Box 1)
  - Valentines Series
    - Elm Street, New Haven, CT, 1911 (Box 1)
  - W. & L. Midas
    - Berkeley Oval, Yale University (Box 1)
  - Weil Novelty Co.
    - "Greetings from Yale", 1905 (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly
    - Memorial Quadrangle, Yale University (Box 1)
  - Unknown publisher, Germany
    - Gymnasium, Yale University (Box 1)
    - Hillhouse Ave., New Haven, CT, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Unknown publlisher
    - Connecticut Hall, Yale University (on leather) (Box 1)
    - Hotel Taft lobby (Box 1)
    - Rock marking first site of Yale U., Old Saybrook (printed for James Pharmacy), 1930 (Box 1)
    - Stuyler's New Haven Store/Campus, Yale, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Sketch of woman in blue with "Yale", 1911 (Box 1)
    - Sketch of woman in blue Y sweater with Y banner and Rah!Rah!Rah!Yale! [on leather], circa 1906 (Box 1)
    - Embroidered Yale emblem, 1907 (Box 1)
  - Non-postcard material
    - Hind's Honey and Almond Cream advertisement [stamp?] with Yale football player being tackled, circa 1920 (Box 1)